[gasps]
How exciting.
You're the one who will
be teaching me this book, yes?
[exclaims softly]
[♪ opening theme song playing]
JAADUGAR
[SORGHAGHTANI] Most incredible.
Now I have my very own copy
of Elements.
OTCHIGIN
And Tolui found it, just for me.
What is your name?
Fatima, that is my name.
I help you in studies, Highness.
Happy to teach things.
I can't wait.
-[SITARA] Although...
-Hm?
I feel confused.
Why is it Highness want book?
It holds not much value.
[SORGHAGHTANI] Huh?
All it does is
just state obvious.
It says, "A point is that
which has no part."
And, "A line
is breadthless length."
You see? It is useless.
Oh.
[SITARA] I'm still not sure
why she ever wanted the book
to begin with.
But I could tell
the prince didn't have any idea
how valuable it really was.
There's a chance
she might part ways with it
if she starts losing interest.
It just states the obvious.
Indeed it does. That's true.
-At least for your people.
-[gasps]
But for us, this book
represents something more,
and it's very special.
By studying its pages,
we will acquire
Western knowledge not found
-on the steppe.
-Huh?
Tolui is the Otchigin
and serves a crucial role.
He's the keeper of the hearth,
watching over its fire.
Even after
his older brothers set off,
and received their own pastures,
as the youngest son,
he remains in the household,
guarding the family fortune
he'll inherit one day.
And because he's the Otchigin,
my husband
will become the emperor.
That said, he isn't exactly
what you might call
the brightest at times.
-[kids laughing]
-But it's not just him.
Many of our people
are the same way.
They know only of life
out here on the steppe.
Vast as it may be,
the world is vaster still,
and I wish to learn more...
about the lands within reach
of Mongol hooves
and the ones even farther.
I've heard
that your people have been able
to successfully
predict the movement
of the stars since antiquity.
How curious!
To think that you're able
to figure out the Earth's size!
Are you saying
this person traveled
to the ends of the Earth?
Of course not.
He just used geometry.
You know what makes
obvious things
seem more obvious?
We prove
all universal principles
after amassing examples
one by one.
I must gain knowledge for all
of our future generations.
As I see it,
that is the role of someone
who will be empress one day.
[Sitara gasps softly]
[SITARA] Oh, why is it...
why is it that she...
Why does she infuriate me so?
Do you even have
the faintest idea
how that book ended up
in your hands?
Do you think you can imagine
the misery and anguish
we must endure
when thanking those
who robbed us of everything
for the charity you now offer?
Do you know nothing
of how I truly feel
as I'm being forced
to sit here at your feet?
Something wrong? I hope
you aren't feeling unwell.
[Sitara cries softly]
No, I admire you.
[Sorghaghtani chuckles softly]
A great pleasure
to serve Highness.
I work hard, I swear.
I'm grateful to have your help,
so thank you.
I know you must be tired.
You may rest now.
I excuse myself.
[Sitara grunts]
Such wisdom as yours
is something
our people desperately need.
[SITARA] I feel ashamed
for wavering back then,
if only for even a moment.
But now...
I mustn't allow myself
to forget this anger inside.
I will never yield...
to that woman.
[wind blowing]
Oh, welcome back, Fatima.
I thank you
for venturing out here
even in this sandstorm.
You're welcome.
Here in Mongolia,
once the sandstorms have passed,
spring will soon follow.
How I miss Persia
in the springtime.
My mother still has
not adjusted well to life here.
[Sitara sighs softly]
-[KHESHIG] Fatima.
-[SITARA] Hm?
[KHESHIG] Princess Sorghaghtani
is asking for you.
She'd like
to begin her studies now.
I would be happy to.
♪
[Sitara grunts]
-[barking]
-[Sitara groans]
Look at your face.
What happened to you?
There are far too many animals
in Mongolia.
And they're nothing
but a big nuisance.
Perhaps so.
But once you get to know them,
they can be rather charming.
Can they now?
[grunting]
Uh... [sighs]
♪
[WOMAN 1] Here you go.
Now just a moment.
It's already
our second winter here.
It appears that your health
is improving, Mother.
[WOMAN 2] Well, I've finally
gotten used to life in Mongolia.
[WOMAN 3] I don't think
I'll ever get used
to this cold weather.
[Sitara whistles]
[sheep bleating]
Tchou, tchou!
SUMMER, A.D. 1224
[SITARA (ADULT)]
Three years had passed
after Sitara became
Princess Sorghaghtani's tutor.
The Mongol army defeated
the Shah of the Khwarazm,
a major power in Central Asia,
and returned in triumph to
their home camp on the steppe.
To welcome them back,
Sorghaghtani and the members
of her court
traveled southwest
of the Altai Mountains
to the basin of the Emil River,
where they feasted and hunted
to celebrate their victory.
[HULEGU] Hey, Father!
[TOLUI] Hulegu! Kublai!
I took down this deer by myself.
And I brought back a hare.
[TOLUI]
You two take after your father.
[HULEGU] Did you see?
This was my first time
to go on a hunt.
-Aren't I so amazing?
-[laughter]
You truly are amazing. [laughs]
Prince Hulegu, Prince Kublai,
the Great Khan will be
arriving here very soon.
Please get ready.
Fatima, see that? Look!
My! That is truly
a splendid deer.
And taking down a nimble hare
is quite impressive as well,
Prince Kublai.
[Kublai chuckles]
Thanks. I guess
all my practicing has paid off.
Who is that girl there?
She's the tutor
who helps me read Elements,
the one you went
and found for me.
Oh, yes,
she's the scholar's daughter.
Is she performing
her duties well?
[SORGHAGHTANI]
I find her to be quite diligent,
-clever, and thoughtful.
-[laughter]
And when I see her smiling
so fetchingly,
I am reminded how young she is.
First,
you brought me Elements,
then a remarkable tutor.
Why yes, of course.
-[HULEGU] Don't I look dashing?
-[laughs]
-[Hulegu grunts]
-And powerful too.
You do know, it is a tradition
after your first hunt
to have the animal's fat rubbed
on your fingers,
and the Great Khan
will do the honors.
[LADY-IN-WAITING]
The Great Khan has arrived.
-[HULEGU] Come on, let's go!
-[KUBLAI] Yeah.
[boys laugh]
[gasps]
♪
[SITARA (ADULT)] The emperor
of the Mongols, Genghis Khan.
It was he who established
this mammoth empire.
In only three years' time,
the fates written in the stars
of those who were present here
would be set into grand motion
and forever changed
after his inevitable fall.
[wind blowing]
SUMMER, A.D. 1227
[TOLUI]
Great Khan... rest assured...
the future of the Mongols
shall be just as you willed it.
Father... [grunts]
♪
[SITARA (ADULT)]
The fourth prince, Tolui,
as the youngest brother,
and Otchigin,
maintained their custom
of ultimogeniture
and inherited the vast majority
of his father,
Genghis Khan's legacy.
In addition to land and fortune,
Tolui's family came to control
almost all
of the imperial Mongol military
and its divisions.
♪
[excited chatter]
[SITARA (ADULT)]
Following the death
of Genghis Khan,
the empire needed to choose
who would be its new ruler.
But the tribal council known
as a Kurultai,
where the imperial clan
and contending princes
gather to elect a new emperor,
wouldn't be convening
for another two years.
During this time,
Tolui didn't just
lead the military,
but all state affairs
while acting as regent.
AUTUMN, A.D. 1229
Doesn't look to be
in the best of health, does it?
That said, it should still be
safe to eat. Let's slaughter it.
[sheep bleats]
That should do it.
Hey, keep on butchering away.
A massive feast like this one
is once in a lifetime.
Here you are. Clean up
all these entrails for me.
[SITARA] In the name of Allah,
and Allah is the greatest.
Uh... Hey, Fatima.
Hmm?
What is it? Does cutting
into the abdomen bother you?
Oh, uh, I'm sorry,
it's just a habit.
Muslims will only eat animals
if their throats
have been cut open first, right?
-Yes.
-But if you do it that way,
you just spill blood
all over the ground.
And draining the blood
makes the meat lose its flavor,
so then you're stuck
eating a bland-tasting meal.
Anyway, we do things
differently here,
so try to put up with us.
Oh, don't worry.
I've already gotten used to it.
I've lived in Mongolia
for eight years now.
I've even come to enjoy eating
unbled meat.
Really?
People who prefer
the taste of meat
that's already been bled
remind me of the sort of people
who prefer sweets
that don't taste too sweet.
I know. Well, you have
entrails to clean.
Thank you, Fatima.
Of course, my pleasure.
♪
[SITARA]
There's actually a good reason
behind butchering an animal
by cutting its throat first.
In the name of Allah,
and Allah is the greatest.
-[slashes]
-[gasps, whimpers]
[ZUMURRUD] It's all right.
That's the most painless method
for the animal.
If the meat
has been drained first,
then it's a much nicer color,
and it doesn't spoil as fast.
♪
[SITARA] Still...
it's no wonder
I've gotten used to dark meat
that hasn't been bled.
Eight years...
That means I've been
living out here in Mongolia
as many years
as I was in Tus.
And yet, after all this time,
I haven't accomplished anything.
That book...
it's been within my grasp
for years now,
but I still haven't
taken it back.
One could hardly say
that I've reclaimed it.
Oh...
There's something hard in here.
[gasps]
Could this be...
[MAN 1] Here. [grunts]
Take this one as well.
[MAN 2] Hm.
It's so strange.
I just can't believe it's him.
Right?
[MAN] That's enough.
Today's a day for celebration.
♪
This is the day our
new emperor's taking the throne.
[exclaims]
Ahh!
[gasps]
[exlaiming]
Instead of using "Khan,"
the new emperor's
calling himself the "Kha'an."
So he's choosing
to bring back an ancient title
that even Genghis Khan
didn't adopt.
The Mongols have risen
to true greatness.
It's a new world,
and Mongolia will soon be
right at the center of it.
[♪ festive music playing]
[both grunt]
-[all cheering]
-[grunts]
As of right now, the Kurultai
has entered its forty-first day.
I guess they must really be
at loggerheads then.
The number forty-one
holds more meaning
than you may be aware of.
Khan's prophecy
said the forty-first day
would be
quite an auspicious one.
I think the prince is about
to be nominated by the clan.
That means today...
he'll take the throne.
Onward, Great Kha'an.
-This way.
-Now our hands will lead you.
GENGHIS KHAN'S YOUNGER BROTHER
TEMÜGE
SECOND PRINCE
CHAGATAI
♪
[BOTH]
Long live the new emperor!
[ALL]
Long live Ögedei Kha'an!
Huzzah!
[ALL] Huzzah!
[Ögedei chuckles softly]
[TOLUI] Great Kha'an!
Today, I must heartily
congratulate you.
Bravo, my brother Ögedei.
Thank you, Tolui.
♪
Someday, from my bloodline,
there may be those who,
if rolled in grass,
wouldn't be eaten by a cow,
nor eaten by a dog
if rolled in fat.
Faced with an elk
emerging crosswise,
and a mouse emerging lengthwise,
they are sure to let both flee.
Now, is it time for celebrating?
My father's will
is to be carried out,
and I'm free
of governing duties.
Ahh!
You did well filling in
all this time.
Sorghaghtani...
the only true regret I have
is knowing
I couldn't make you empress.
Oh, don't say that.
I mean, when Father
shared his will with us,
I couldn't help but think,
"Why? Shouldn't it
have been me instead?"
But this is how he explained it.
"When a many-headed snake
tries to enter a burrow
to outlast the cold,
the heads fight each other,
and it soon dies
without making it inside.
Conversely, a serpent
with one head
will burrow inside
and easily survive."
"Ögedei, use your brains
to become the head for us all."
[exclaims]
Being the Otchigin,
I began to assume he favored me
over the others.
But no, that isn't what
Father was thinking at all.
The great power
he bestowed upon me
wasn't simply for me alone.
There's one thing that will make
the Mongols strong,
and it's the bond we share
as brothers.
That is what my father,
Genghis Khan,
wished for.
It is my greatest wish as well.
[SORGHAGHTANI]
Your brotherly bond.
[Sitara sighs]
It doesn't matter to me
which one of the brothers
sits on the throne
as the emperor.
But breaking years of tradition
just to have him succeed you?
Prince Ögedei couldn't possibly
be more qualified.
[chuckles]
Seems Shira
backed the wrong horse.
In any case, the Kurultai can
finally come to an end now.
[gasps]
Is this stone
truly what I think it is?
I read about it in
one of my mistress's books.
It's extremely valuable.
[SORGHAGHTANI] Fatima?
[SITARA] Princess Sorghaghtani?
[SITARA] Uh, what's the matter?
I have something important
to discuss.
With me?
After tonight,
I no longer want you
to be by my side anymore.
Wait... What?
How could this be?
You think I've done
something wrong, is that it?
It is nothing like that at all.
Then what could it be?
[Sitara grunts]
Hmm?
Fatima, I want you...
to act as a spy for me.
[Sitara gasps]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[SITARA (ADULT)] Next time,
"A Snake Shows Its Colors.
Man Hides His Colors."